Lesson nine is resource management.
So these are some of the learning
objectives for resource management.
However, resource management is also
another huge topic.
This is something that PMI have really
expanded for the new exam.
So we've divided this up into two parts as
well.
So lesson nine is resource
management part one, and
then lesson 10 will be
resource management part two.
All right, so learning objectives then for
part one, right?
We want to understand the difference between
physical resources and team resources.
Resources on your project include things
like equipment, supplies, labor,
raw materials.
So which one of those are physical
resources?
Which one of those are team resources?
And what's the difference?
Why do you want to have these two
different categories?
We'll be discussing that.
You also need to identify the different
roles on a project, very important.
Right?
PMI have several roles.
You want to understand what all the roles
are.
And because the roles are
different based on whether
it's a predictive project
and an agile project.
So you need to be able to distinguish
between the two.
Also, one of the important
artifacts we're going to be
talking about is this one
here called the team charter.
The team charter, we have a separate video
on the team charter.
It's a very important document,
a very important artifact.
You need to understand the purpose of
that.
Appreciate the purpose of the team
charter.
And then in Agile, we
talk about two types of
skills called T-shaped
skills and I-shaped skills.
So you want to understand
then, what are the difference
in the T-shaped skills
and the I-shaped skills?
And which one of those skills will be
relevant for Agile projects.